不是说看阴道吗
Yo, I thought I was going to see some, like, vaginas.
我没说她画的是阴道
I didn't say she actually painted vaginas.
我是说
I said
她画的东西
some of her paintings
看着像阴道
looked like vaginas.
真的吗
Uh, seriously?
这差的太远了吧
Not even close.
乔治亚·欧姬芙能画出任何东西
Georgia O'Keeffe painted all kinds of stuff.
她周围的任何事物
Everyday items, her surroundings.
有些作品能唤起人的性欲
Some of it evoked an erotic nature.
这就是她
It's who she was.
我见过的阴道没一个长这样的
Not like any vagina I ever saw.
她精神正常吗
This chick have medical issues?
这幅画...
This particular painting--
是扇门
...is of a door.
这儿还有其他门可以看看吗
Any other doors we can check out?
比如真的门...
Like, real ones or...
我还是没搞明白
You know, I-I-I don't get it.
为什么有人会画门
Why would anyone paint a picture of a door
还不厌其烦地画那么多次
over and over again, like, dozens of times?
因为都不一样啊
But it wasn't the same.
不  那都一样
Uh, yeah, it was.
虽然主题都是门  但作品是在变化的
It was the same subject, but it was different every time.
每次的灯光不同
The light was different.
每次画家的心情不同
Her mood was different.
她每次作画  都有新的元素
She saw something new every time she painted it.
这还不算神经病吗
And that's not psycho to you?
照你这说法  那我们为什么要反复做同一件事
Well, then, why should we do anything more than once?
那我是不是该只抽这一支烟
Should I just smoke this one cigarette?
或者只做一次爱
Maybe we should only have sex once if it's the same thing.
别
Whoa, no--
只看得到一次日落吗
Should we just watch one sunset?
还是只活一天
Or live just one day.
因为每天都是崭新的
Because it's new every time.
每次都是新的经历
Each time, it's a different experience.
好了  行了
Okay, fine.
我觉得那幅牛的头骨还好
I guess the cow skull pictures were cool,
但门的话
but a door?
我还是那看法
I will say it again.
一扇门
A door.
门怎么了嘛
Why not a door?
有时你对事物恋恋不忘
Sometimes you get fixated on something,
而你却可能不知道为什么
and you might not even get why.
你发散思维  顺其自然地展开想象
You open yourself up and go with the flow,
天马行空地想象
wherever the universe takes you.
好吧  然后她天马行空地想到了门
Okay, so the universe took her to a door,
还迷恋上了门
and she got all obsessed with it
还强迫自己画了20次  直到它完美无缺
and just had to paint it 20 times until it was perfect.
我可没这么说  因为人无完人  金无足赤
No, I wouldn't say that. Nothing's perfect.
是吗
Yeah?
有的
Oh, yeah.
有些事就很完美
Some things.
真甜蜜
Oh, that was so sweet,
不过我刚才呕吐了一点在嘴里
I think I threw up in my mouth a little bit.
要你承认一次我是对的就那么难吗
You can't admit just for once that I'm right.
有那么难吗
Come on.
那叫欧姬芙的女人一次又一次地在尝试
That O'Keeffe lady kept trying over and over
直到把那烂门画到最完美
until that stupid door was perfect.
不  那门代表她的家  她对它有感情
No. That door was her home, and she loved it.
对我而言  最重要的就是留住那种感觉
To me, that's about making that feeling last.
绝
命
毒
师
第三季
第十一集
好了  要开始了  准备好了吗
All right, here we go. You ready?
加油  走一步  一步就好
Come on, give me a step. Give me one step.
不行
Nope.
不行  不行  拉我上去
Nope, that's it. Take me up.
汉克  你能行的
You can do this, Hank.
加油  痛是正常的
Come on, it's supposed to hurt.
要重新走路当然很痛
Pain is weakness leaving your body.
我一脚揣你屁股里才叫痛  玛丽
Pain is my foot in your ass, Marie.
要你的脚真能抬那么高  尽管放马过来
Hey, if you can get your leg up that high, I say go for it.
-拉我上去  上去  -好  休息一下
- Take me up. Take me up. - All right, coffee break.
休息一分钟
We're gonna let you rest for a minute,
然后再来一次
and then we're gonna try it again.
不用了
Never mind about your coffee break.
赶紧拉我上去  疼死我了  我受够了
Take me up. I'm done. I'm done.
好吧  脱下来吧
Well, this picked up a very left-off.
加油  汉克叔叔  你能行的
Come on, Uncle Hank. You can do it.
不然你怎么出得了院
How else are you going to get out of here?
你就没有朋友吗
Don't you have any friends?
天  你就没正事做吗
I mean Jesus, find something better to do.
我不需要你们看到我被挂在这儿
I don't need everyone staring at me
像骆驼的驼峰一样
hanging here like a camel's ball sack.
汉克  他只是想给你点鼓励
Hank, he just wants to be supportive.
没关系
It's all right.
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
好吗  我很快回来
Okay? I'll be right back.
你们打算什么时候把我弄下来
You gonna get me out of here sometime today?
斯凯
Sky--
我收到账单了
We got our first bill,
如果你还坚持...
and, you know, if you're still insistent--
当然坚持
I am.
作好准备
Prepare yourself.
接下来每周都会有账单  所以
They're gonna start coming in weekly like that, so...
没问题
Okay.
你确定你能搞定吗
You're sure you can do this?
是的
Yeah.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：zlean     soda     Silmar     花零落
时间轴：Angelica     特效：Will     校对：凤姐
■
后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
我来吧
I'll do that.
这是干嘛
What the hell, man?
现在连量都不让我来了吗
What, I can't work a scale now?
这太他妈扯淡了
This is bullshit.
你就直说了吧
Just say it.
直说了吧
Just say the words.
-你认为我偷东西  -嘘
- You think I'm stealing. - Shhh.
走你自己的路
Walk with who you are.
我以前的赞助者经常这么对我说
That was a phrase my sponsor used to use with me
那还是我刚参加戒毒互助会的时候
back when I first started coming to meetings.
这可能是"做你自己"的另一种说法罢了
It's probably just a different way of saying "Be yourself."
对吧
Right?
但这个"走"法
But this idea of "Walk"
还告诉我
also tells me
生活还将继续
that I have to move forward.
他总是给我有用的忠告
Always good advice, at least for me.
我看这里来了些新人
I see we have some new people here at group,
新面孔
a couple new faces.
举个手
Let's see some hands.
谁是新来的
First time?
好的  欢迎
Great. Welcome.
我们可以轮流自我介绍下
Maybe we can go around, introduce ourselves.
想到什么尽管说
Say whatever's on your mind.
从你开始怎么样  可以吗
How about you? You want to start us off?
可以  我叫安德里亚
Yeah. My name is Andrea... and, uh...
我们又不会咬人  不会做评判
We don't bite. No judgments.
你可以畅所欲言
You can be as open and honest as you want to be.
老实说  我不想来这
Honestly, I don't want to be here.
好吧  够诚实
All right. Fair enough.
还有谁有话要说
Who else had their hand up?
你好
Hey. 'Sup?
我是杰西
My name's Jesse.
你好
Why, hello.
我叫布兰登
My name is Brandon.
我想这位是彼得吧
And this is, I believe, Peter?
没错  我是彼得  你好
Right. I'm Peter. How are you?
知会你们一声
Look, I just wanted to give you a heads up.
偷运毒品的事可能要缓一缓
It's gonna get a little slower smuggling product
臭老头在监视我的一举一动
with Grandpa Anus watching every move I make.
别担心  我会搞定的
But don't worry. I'll keep it flowing.
-好的  -很好
- Great. - Right on.
那好
Yeah.
卖的怎么样
So how's it selling?
很好吧
Mad volume?
是的  情况...
Yeah. It's, uh...
你知道的...
You know, it's, um...
不怎么样
It's not so good.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你卖了多少
How much have you sold?
1.75克
I sold a teenth.
One teenth?
就这么点吗
That's it?
是的
Yeah.
卖谁了
To who?
他
To him.
听着  卖给这些人可不太容易
Look, it's not so easy selling to these people.
他们都是些想改过自新的人
They're here trying to better themselves.
肯定是这样的  就这么回事
Yeah, there's, like, positivity and stuff going on here.
我在外面拼上性命给你们俩搞来毒品
I'm out risking my ass to get product for you two,
而你们两个孬种却卖不掉
and you're too pussy to sell?
可怜虫
You're pathetic.
把货都给我  全部都给我
You know what? I want it back. All of it.
我自己卖
I'll sell it myself.
得了  伙计  别这样
Come on, man. Don't be like that.
卖毒品给这些人
Selling to these people,
就像用枪打婴儿
it's like shooting a baby in the face.
太难下手了
It's not natural.
没错  杰西  没你想的那么容易
Yeah, Jesse, it's not easy like you think.
那我就证明给你们看那有多容易
I'll show you exactly how easy it is.
对不起
Oh, hey. Sorry.
没关系  继续
No. Go ahead.
是安德里亚吗
It's Andrea, right?
是的
Yeah.
你好  我是杰西
Hey, um, my name's Jesse,
我也不想呆在这里
and, uh, I don't really want to be here, either.
抱歉
Sorry.
玛丽姨妈要来吃晚饭吗
Aunt Marie's coming to dinner?
她不来
No.
你爸爸要来
Your dad is.
你有什么窍门让她这么快入睡
How'd you get her to sleep so quick?
是不是因为你很无聊
Are you that boring?
我让她感到安逸
I'm comforting.
她觉得在我怀里很安逸
I'm a comforting presence.
睡吧
There we go.
乖
Shh, shh.
看
Hey, so check it out.
什么
Huh?
知道这意味着什么吗
See what that means?
看看日期
Check out the date.
我正式宣布  到下周四
Next Thursday is officially six months
我持初学驾照就有半年了
that I have had my learner's,
表示我可以领到临时驾照
which means I can get my provisional
可以自己开车了
and start driving by myself.
什么时候的事儿
Since when?
你还有两个月才满十六周岁呢
You don't turn 16 for two more months.
这是临时的  年龄无所谓
It doesn't matter. It's a provisional.
查查  法律修改过了  10年前的事了
Look it up. They changed the law, like, 10 years ago.
是吗  我当时可没投赞成票
Oh, yeah? Well, I didn't vote for that.
你投不投票无所谓
Doesn't matter if you voted for it.
法律就是法律
It's the law.
所以你俩可以开始想想
So both of you start thinking
打算给我买辆什么样的车了
about what kind of car you want to buy me.
要是有老款IROC跑车或者福特野马
I think I'd be good with either
我就满意了
an old IROC or a 'Stang.
福特野马啊
Ah, a 'Stang.
车轮辐板上有扑克牌的怎么样
How about something with playing cards in the spokes?
可以发出嗤嗤声
Makes a nice motor-y sound, you know?
要打发我可没那么容易
Aha, dad. You're not gonna get off that easy.
我想这件事...
Well, I-- I think that this is, um--
过会儿再来讨论
We should probably table this discussion for later.
你爸爸和我有些事
Your dad and I have a couple things
要谈  所以...
we need to talk about, so--
好的
Okay.
1971年款  340马力  快背设计
A 1971 Mach 1 fastback
绿黄色
in Grabber Lime
前盖要带振动系统的
with a shaker hood.
福特野马
'Stang.
我要写下来免得忘了
I want to write that down so I don't forget.
郁闷  没笔
Oh, darn it. No pencil!
北极斑马科考站合作人是怎么回事
What is Ice Station Zebra Associates?
是外贷  没问题的
It's a loan-out. It's fine.
外贷给谁
Whose loan-out?
没事的  真的
It's fine. Really.
我有个熟人
I...have a guy.
那
Okay.
你的熟人知道
Um, does your guy know
新墨西哥州的所得税的法律法规吗
the tax code and regulations in New Mexico?
因为这笔钱每季度都要查
'Cause there's very specific paperwork
而且还要明细上报
that has to be submitted quarterly on this.
他知道  我这个熟人是个...行家
Yes. My guy is a top...guy.
他是谁
Who is he?
叫什么名字
Uh. What's his name?
他够格吗
What are his qualifications?
沃尔特
Walt,
这笔钱到汉克和玛丽手里时
this money has to be unimpeachable
必须是正当的
when it reaches Hank and Marie.
这笔钱是正当的  现在是将来也是
And it is. It will be.
可你叫我怎么放心
But how do I know that?
你连这个人的名字都不能告诉我
I mean, apparently, you can't even tell me the man's name.
老天
Oh. Jesus.
斯凯勒  你真的想知道吗
Skyler, do you really want to know?
我是说  当真想知道吗
I mean, do you really want to know?
真想吗
Really?
你们好  欢迎
Hello. Welcome.
很荣幸见到你
What a pleasure it is to have you.
可以的话  我就叫你斯凯勒了
I'm just gonna call you Skyler, if that's okay.
名字很可爱
It's a lovely name.
让我想起晴空万里
Reminds me of a big beautiful sky.
沃尔特从没告诉过我他有多幸运
Walt never told me how lucky he was--
当然  最近发生了点小意外
prior to recent unfortunate events.
显然  他选女人
Clearly, his taste in women
和选律师是同样的品味
is the same as his taste in lawyers--
只选最好的
only the very best
同时也是有点肮脏的
with just the right amount of dirty.
开玩笑呢
That's a joke.
挺有趣  因为很显然  你的格调很高
It's funny because you are so clearly very classy.
来吧  请坐
Here. Please, sit down.
沃尔特告诉我
So Walt tells me
我可以帮你消除一些顾虑
that you have some concerns I can alleviate.
是的  我有
Uh, yes, I do. I have...
顾虑
concerns.
如果我们要继续这么下去
If we're going to go down this road,
当然  是为了我的妹夫着想
and clearly we are for the sake of my brother-in-law.
我听说了他的事
I've heard about him.
他是真英雄
He's an American hero.
至少  我需要一些保证
At any rate, I need some assurances
确保我们所办之事是
that we're gonna go about this in a manner
安全谨慎的
that is extremely safe and cautious.
可以理解  我来给你梳理一遍程序
Fair enough. I'll walk you through the process.
第一步
First step is something
我们把它叫做洗钱
we like to call money laundering, all right?
我们拿了你们的钱  就用这些豆粒糖来代表
Take your money, represented by, say, these jelly beans.
-我是会计  -然后...
- You know, I'm a bookkeeper-- - Then I--
所以我知道什么是洗钱
...so I actually know what money laundering is.
-好吧  -没错
- Well... - Yeah.
正如大部分事情一样
And, as with most things,
细节决定成败
the devil is in the details.
我首先要知道
So to begin with,
这笔钱的来路  我们要怎么说
what are we saying is the source of this money?
这很简单
That's simple.
沃尔特编了个很好的故事
Walt here actually came up with a great story
说是赌赢的钱
about gambling winnings.
21点  对吧  算牌
Blackjack, right? Some card counting?
其实  这是斯凯勒的主意
Well, actually, that was Skyler's idea.
好吧
Well,
你真是越来越魅力四射了
you grow more gorgeous by the minute.
那么就是这样
Well, there you have it.
我会伪造大量的现金转帐记录
I'll generate false currency transaction reports out the wazoo.
这与填写赌博所得收入的表格同等重要
as well as the necessary W-2Gs.
我认识几个赌场经理
I know a couple casino managers
他们会抓住机会上报伪造的亏损
who will jump at the chance to report false losses.
这是双赢的局面
It's a win-win for everyone.
是可以这样  但可不是长久之计
Yeah, but you can't sell that for very long.
没错  我早想到了
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Way ahead of you.
我们部分申报纳税到不引起怀疑就够了
We declare just enough so as not to arouse suspicion,
然后沃尔特赢得这笔钱就成了
then Walt's one-time winnings become seed money
一项投资的本钱
for an investment.
投资什么
Investment in what?
隆重的时刻到来  听我告诉你
Drum roll please. Wait for it.
激光枪战游戏
Laser tag.
7000平方英尺的游乐场
7,000 square feet of rollicking fun
开在伯纳利欧县北部中心地带
in the heart of northern Bernlillo County.
激光枪战游戏
Laser tag?
是啊  枪枝弹药  火光大炮
Yeah. There's guns and glow lights and--
穿着防弹背心的小孩儿
Kids wear the vests,
互相组队...
and they have to split into teams--
我知道那是什么
Right. No, actually, I know what it is.
只是把这与沃尔特联系起来
It's just that in relation to Walt, it's--
不太靠谱
I mean, it doesn't make any sense.
这比说你们俩是一对儿靠谱多了
It makes more sense than you two being together.
我始终想不通你俩是怎么走到一起的
I'm still trying to figure out how that happened.
你很了解沃尔特吗
Do you even know Walt? I mean...
他怎么可能做起激光枪战游戏这种生意
how would he of all people buy a laser tag business?
和他身份不符
It doesn't add up.
和他身份正合适  沃尔特是科学家
It adds up perfectly. Walt's a scientist.
科学家喜欢激光
Scientists love lasers.
况且还有碰碰船呢
Plus they got bumper boats, so--
嘿  大伙儿知道吗
Hey, everybody.
沃尔特突然决定投资激光枪战游戏了
Walt suddenly decided to invest in laser tag.
纯粹是异想天开
Just out of the blue.
像这样吗  我们就这样告诉别人
Really? That's what we're supposed to tell people,
我们的家人  朋友  政府
our family, our friends, the government?
我来给你明确一下
Let me bottom line this for you.
你不必牵涉其中
You don't need to be involved.
因为我干这行已经好多年了
Because I've been doing this for a lot of years--
没有你的帮助  我也很成功
successfully, believe it or not--
信不信由你
without your help.
感谢两位前来
So thank you for stopping by.
要来瓶啤酒还是别的
You want a beer or something?
别的
Or something.
你有什么别的
What do you mean?
比如啤酒
Like beer.
我戒了毒  没别的了
I'm clean out of anything else.
即使我有别的  我们也不该吸
Even if I wasn't, we're not supposed to.
是啊
Yeah.
我听这话已经一遍
I've heard it over
一遍
and over
又一遍了
and over again.
你觉不觉得很荒谬
You know, don't you think it's ridiculous
这个社会允许我们喝啤酒
that society says beer is okay
来点劲爆的就不行
and a little hit of something sweet is wrong?
我是指
I mean...
为什么要忍着不吸那些
what's the point of shutting yourself off completely
能让人飘飘欲仙的东西
from something that lifts you off the ground?
我花了很大的精力
I spend so much energy
压制自己想吸的欲望
fighting the urge not to use,
但感觉很糟
and I feel like crap because of it.
我知道  只是...
I know. It's just...
什么
What?
我不能再被发现复吸
I can't get caught using again.
那别被抓住就行了
See, the thing is... not to get caught.
你试过那个蓝色的货吗
You ever try that blue stuff that's going around?
小吸一口
Just a little gas in the tank,
一瞬间
and suddenly...
一切变得无与伦比
everything is interesting.
我多希望这种感觉可以一直持续下去
Man, I wish I can make that feeling last.
我刚说了  这儿什么都没有
Like I said, I got nothing here.
要是我能弄点儿来呢
What if I could get some?
妈咪  妈咪
Mommy! Mommy!
嘿  小布
Hey, B!
奶奶早早儿把你领回来了
Oh, your nana brought you home early.
奶奶  我以为今天布鲁克去你那儿
Grandma, I thought you were keeping Brock today.
是的  但我看见你的车
I was. Then I saw your car.
你不是去戒毒互助会了吗
I thought you had a meeting.
对  改时间了
I did, but we changed the time.
外婆  这是杰西
Grandma, this is Jesse.
互助会的成员
He's from the meeting.
算是发起者
He's like a sponsor.
杰西  这是外婆
Jesse, this is Grandma.
杰西  这是布鲁克
Jesse, this is Brock.
这么说  你...
So, you, uh...
你有孩子
You have a kid, huh?
你好吗
What's up?
布鲁克是吗
Brock, huh?
这名字真酷
That's a cool name.
来  击掌
Here. Give it up.
布鲁克快满6岁了
Brock is almost 6.
你不讨厌孩子吧
You okay with kids?
啥  不  他挺好的
What? Yeah, he's cool.
好  我们大人说话
Okay, Brock is gonna go play in his room
布鲁克回房间去玩
while the big people talk.
去玩乐高积木和小汽车
He's gonna go play with his Legos and his cars
-说"杰西再见"  -杰西再见
- Say "Bye, Jesse." - Bye, Jesse.
我所要求的  不过是谨慎安全
Safe and cautious, that's all I'm asking,
那个人却完全不靠谱
and that man is neither.
我承认  他看起来就像个小丑
I'll admit, he comes across like a circus clown.
但他知道自己在做什么
But he actually knows what he's doing.
你完全不要牵连进来
Safe and cautious is you
这才是谨慎安全
not being involved in this at all.
那可有点来不及了
Well, it's a little late on that.
你用制毒赚的钱付家里账单开始
This is what happens when you decide
我已是共犯
to pay our bills with drug money.
斯凯勒  这事涉及的不止是之前的事情
Skyler, this isn't just about what happened before.
我现在正越陷越深
My involvement in this is ongoing.
你明白吗
Understand?
没有回头路可走了
I can't just quit.
我签了某种算得上合同的东西
I have something of a contract.
非常安全  专业  组织严密
It's all very safe and professional and structured.
我不可能轻易脱身
I can't simply quit.
你往哪儿开
Where are you going?
沃尔特  如果你一定要洗钱
If you're gonna launder money, Walt,
至少得选对方式
at least do it right.
洗车场
你在这里工作过4年
You worked here four years.
了解这个行业
It's a business you understand.
人们会相信
It's a story people will believe.
激光枪战不靠谱  这个靠谱
Not laser tag. This.
这才是我们该买的
This is what we buy.
你
You.
这才是你该买的
This is what you buy.
杰西是吧
Hey, uh, Jesse, right?
布兰登  彼得
Brandon. Peter.
最近怎么样  混得还成
How goes it? Hanging in there?
得了省省吧  蠢猪
Please, just... Dumb ass.
不好意思伙计  我是想打打掩护
Sorry, man. I was trying to keep it on the DL.
你和那个妞  搞成了吗
So you and that girl, you do the deed yet?
搞什么
Do what?
你知道的  就是把货卖给她
You know, sell to her.
你们两个跑来干嘛
What are you two even doing here?
什么意思
What do you mean?
既然你们没本事把货卖出去
You can't get your nut up to sell.
还跑来干嘛
What's the point of even coming?
老兄  我已经进行到第五步了
Homie, I'm on, like, step 5.
我也是
Deuce, yo.
我正迎头赶上呢
I'm catching up.
随你们便吧
Whatever.
回见
Later.
哥们得赶紧了
Dude needs to come into the fold.
就是
Yep.
知道吗
Oh, you know what,
我可有超能力哦
I have magical powers.
要不要看
You want to see?
准备好了吗
Ready?
不是真的
That's not real.
是真的
It is real.
你要看真的吗
All right, do you want to see something that's real?
看这个  瞧仔细了
Look at this. Watch this.
准备好了
Ready?
喜欢吗
You like that?
这叫科学  科学规律使然
That's science and stuff. Makes it do that.
再来一次
Do it again.
让杰西吃饭吧  布鲁克
Let Jesse eat his dinner, Brock.
没关系
It's okay.
要再看一遍吗
Want to see it again?
你会用鞭炮变戏法吗
Could you do a trick with firecrackers?
鞭炮
Firecrackers.
这个  我身上没带鞭炮
You know, I don't have any firecrackers on me.
谁会用鞭炮变戏法
Who does tricks with firecrackers?
托马斯
Tomás
托马斯会用鞭炮变戏法
Tomás does tricks with firecrackers, huh?
托马斯是谁
Who's Tomás?
我家小弟
He's my kid brother.
是嘛
Yeah?
我们不怎么提他
And we don't talk about him.
乖  吃饭吧  布鲁克
Come on. Eat your food, Brock.
我可以吃根薯条吗
Can I have a chip?
我要偷你的薯条了
I'm gonna steal your chip.
嘿  那是我的
Hey, that's mine.
就这个吗  这就是你要买的产业
That's it? That's what you want to buy?
这个至少比较可信
People will believe it at least.
我在这里工作过4年
I worked here for four years.
打蜡  去蜡  这是你干的吗
Wax on, wax off. Was that you?
为什么你们总给车里喷空气清新剂呢
Hey, how come you guys always get with the air freshener, huh?
我特地嘱咐说不要喷空气清新剂
I explicitly say I want no air freshener,
每次来取车的时候
and every time I drive away
车里都香得跟妓院似的
smelling like an Alpine whore house.
无意冒犯  我看不出哪里好  所以不行
All due respect, I don't see it. So I vote, I vote no.
比你那激光枪战靠谱一些
Makes a better story than your laser tag.
这是你的意思还是你家那位的主意
Is that you talking or Yoko Ono?
她说的有道理
She has a point.
我投资这里更说得通
It makes more sense that I invest right here.
说得好像她洗了很多年的钱一样
Based on her years of experience in money laundering, I suppose.
我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
只要功夫深  什么故事都能真
If you're committed enough, you can make any story work.
我曾让一个女人相信我就是凯文·科斯纳
I once convinced a woman that I was Kevin Costner.
著名的演员 导演兼制片人
诀窍就是自己要深信不疑
And it worked because I believed it.
跟故事好不好没关系
It has nothing to do with the story.
另外  这破地方压根不成
Besides, this dump isn't gonna work
因为这里没有丹尼
because it doesn't have a Danny.
懂吗  这里没有丹尼
Okay? There's no Danny here.
这个他妈的丹尼是谁
What in God's name is a Danny?
丹尼是激光枪战游乐场的老板
Danny runs the laser tag.
他是个眼光独特的人
Danny is the guy who had a vision.
别人只看到一堆破烂
Where others saw a dirt lot,
他却能看到黑光灯  塑胶外星人
he saw black lights, rubber aliens,
青少年拿着激光枪跑来跑去  懂吗
teenagers running around with ray guns, right?
就像沙漠里的毕斯·西格尔[美国黑帮老大]
It was like Bugsy Siegel in the desert.
股票崩盘以后  丹尼有麻烦了
And when the stock market took a shit and Danny got into trouble,
他就开始寻找我们这种
he went searching for exactly the type of situation
合作伙伴
that we're offering.
丹尼是懂得变通  从而实现梦想的人
Danny will look the other way to keep his dream afloat.
换句话说  丹尼完全可以信任
In other words, Danny can be trusted completely.
那家伙  看眉毛就是个直肠子
That guy... the guy with the eyebrows that won't quit...
能做丹尼吗
is he a Danny?
你买下这地方
You buy this place,
就是一幢会喷水的大楼
all you got is a big building that squirts water.
这里没有丹尼
You got no Danny here.
想留下吃晚饭吗
You want to stay for dinner?
想
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
几点了
What time is it?
还早呢
Early still.
那么
So...
什么
What?
我在想
I thought maybe,
如果你不走的话
if you're holding,
我们或许可以做点什么
we can do something.
做什么
What?
就是  之前你提到的蓝色的那货
You know, that blue stuff you were talking about?
或许你手头有点
Maybe you had a line on some.
等等  你说什么
Wait. Whoa. What?
你不是说孩子快回来了吗
I thought you said the kid is coming home.
没错  不是还有几个小时吗
Yeah, in a few hours.
所以你真的想嗑药
And you seriously want to get high?
我不明白你为什么这样生气
I don't know what you're getting so pissed about.
那天是你先提起来的
You're the one who brought it up the other day.
的确  但那是我知道你有孩子之前的事
Yeah, that was before I found out you got a kid.
你算哪门子母亲
What kind of mother are you?
什么
What?
你听见了  孩子要你照顾  你却嗑药鬼混
You heard me. What kind of mom gets wasted
你算哪门子母亲
with a little kid to take care of?
谁也没资格说我没好好照顾我儿子
Nobody can say I don't take care of my son.
你还跑我家来批判我吗
You gonna come in my house and judge me?
你是不是觉得你自己无牵无挂
Like you got no responsibility,
所以可以随便嗑药
so it's okay for you to get high.
-听着  我  -你了解我多少
- Look, I... - What do you know about me?
我的孩子  我知道照顾
I take care of my baby.
我愿意为他做任何事情
I'll do anything for him.
布鲁克出生的那天  我发过誓
The day Brock was born, I swore...
绝不会让我儿子重蹈托马斯的覆辙
I won't let what happened to Tomás happen to my son.
除非我死
I'll die first.
对不起  我...
Sorry. I...
我只是
I just...
如果你想我离开  我马上就走
Look, I'll get out of here if you want.
你要想走  那就走吧
That's what you want to do, then go.
我不想走
It's not what I want.
听着  我的话太过分了
Look, I was out of line talking about that stuff.
我俩都有错
We both were.
你说得对
You're right.
我不知道你经历过什么
I don't know what you've been through.
如果你愿意  可以告诉我
Yo can tell me if you want.
整个街坊都被黑帮控制着
This whole neighborhood is run by gangs.
他们贩毒  控制街道
They run the drugs, control the streets.
他们把托马斯拉进去了
And they sort of took Tomás in.
托马斯当时8岁  没父亲看管  跟他们学坏了
No dad around. 8 years old, they got Tomás slinging.
加入了某个帮派
Part of some crew.
到他十岁的时候
Then, when he was 10...
为了什么入会仪式
for some initiation or something...
要他去杀个人
they made him kill somebody.
我一开始听到传言并不相信
I heard the rumors. I didn't believe it at first.
但一个礼拜后我遇到他
But then I saw him, like, a week later.
他告诉我传言是真的
He told me, yeah, he did it.
他们给了他把枪
They gave Tomás a gun.
让他选
Gave him a choice.
自杀还是杀别人
Him or some dude.
所以他选择杀别人
So he did it.
他说得轻描淡写的
Told me all about it like it was nothing.
他有说他杀了谁吗
Who did he say he killed?
一个其他组织的毒贩吧
Some dealer...from some outside crew.
就在那边的街角
Right around the corner from here,
中心再过去一点的地方
over off the Central.
他就骑着他的脚踏车然后开枪杀了他
Just rode up on his bike and shot him.
中心再过去一点吗
Off the Central?
你是说铁轨那边吗
Like, over by the train tracks?
什么时候的事
When was this?
几个月前吧
A few months back.
他还说什么了
What else did he tell you?
他开枪射穿了那人的脖子
He shot the guy right through the neck.
那人当场就死了
Shot him dead.
就因为他在别人的地盘贩毒
Just because he was working the wrong corner.
这种事绝不能再在我儿子身上发生
It won't happen again. Not to my son.
你猜怎样
Guess what.
当人们说"猜"的时候
People who say "Guess what"
他们确实想要你去猜
and then actually expect you to guess--
我讨厌这种人
I hate those people.
好吧  我刚听说
Well, I just heard
一个叫做汉克·施拉德的病人
about a certain patient named Schrader-comma-Hank
这周末就可以出院了
who is going to be released at the end of this week.
开心吗
Isn't that fantastic?
他们终于打算让我出院了
Are they planning on rolling me out the front door at least,
是不是打算在窗户边架个木板
or they'll put me on a greased plank
好让我滑下去
and, uh, slide me out the window?
听着  我才不管
Listen, I don't care
那些该死的保险公司说什么
what any damned insurance company thinks.
我痊愈之前绝不离开这里
I'm not leaving here until I'm well.
汉克  这不关保险的事儿
Hank, this isn't about insurance.
我和医生们都谈过了
I've talked to everybody, and they all say
他们都说你复原得不错  可以回家了
that you are healthy enough to go home.
我康复的不错  是吗
Oh, I'm healthy enough, huh? Yeah.
汉克  你的状况一天比一天好了
Hank, you get stronger every day.
不需要再待在医院里了
You don't need to be in a hospital.
就现在这状况  我宁愿待在医院里
In this condition, yeah, I do.
你回家会跟在这里一样舒服的
You'll be just as comfortable at home as you are here.
这儿有的设备家里都有...
You'll have all the same equipment--
家里都有  什么意思
All the same equipment? What--
-所以你在这  -你的意思是
- The equipment-- ...- Does that mean?
你用得到的东西  家里都有
...that you have here that you need.
只是暂时的
Short term.
你可以在家做体能训练
You'll do your PT at home,
这很好  不是吗  毕竟在家里
and it'll be great because you'll be home.
还有卧室
Wait till you see the bedroom.
我叫他们把等离子电视也搬过来了
I had them move the plasma in.
我知道你一直想要那东西
I know that's how you always wanted it,
所以你才故意中枪来医院的  对吧
and you only had to get shot to get it, right?
我还给你买了张新床
I got you a new bed.
病床吗
A hospital bed?
是啊
Well--
你在我卧室里放了张病床吗
You put a hospital bed in my bedroom?
汉克  这样你就能回家了
Hank, you'll be home.
你给我把那东西扔掉
You get that out of my house.
听到了吗  玛丽
You hear me, Marie?
今天就扔掉
Today.
汉克
Hank--
等我能走的时候
I leave this hospital
我才出院  你明白了吗
when I walk out of here, you understand?
在此之前  绝对不走
And not before.
丹尼是什么人
What's a Danny?
丹尼是帮我们洗钱的人
Danny is an accomplice, someone who's in on the scheme,
他知道怎么洗钱
who knows about laundering,
我们付钱给他  帮我们另谋出路洗钱
who's paid to look the other way.
虽然我同意你的说法
Now, while I agree with you
激光枪战游乐场的确不是好主意
that laser tag is a hard sell,
但如果没那人帮忙
without a Danny,
洗车场的事也是做不成的
the car wash isn't really an option.
他没法再给你找个丹尼
And he can't get you another Danny
来打理洗车场吗
to run the car wash?
说起来简单
Easier said than done,
但想找个可信的人是很难的
if we're looking for someone trustworthy.
我怎么样
What about me?
什么你怎么样
What about you?
我来
Me.
我来帮你洗钱
I'll be the Danny.
不  不  斯凯勒  这不是个好主意
No. No. No, Skyler. That is not a good idea.
我完全有能力来管理这种小生意
I'm perfectly capable of managing a small business.
那也得是合法生意  不是这种生意
A legal business, not this.
那我们还能相信谁
Who else could we trust?
-不行  -沃尔特
- No. - Walt.
我已经被牵扯进来了
I'm in this.
所以我来做  就可以万无一失了
And if I'm in it, I'm going to do it right.
你没有  这和你无关
You are not in this. You are not--
咱俩是夫妻  怎么会无关
We're married. How am I not in this?
我们不是夫妻  斯凯勒  我们离婚了
We are not married, Skyler. We're divorced.
对吗
Right?
其实我还没来得及提交离婚协议书
I never actually got around to filing the papers.
夫妻不能被强迫出庭指证对方的
Married couples can't be compelled to testify against one another.
所以就这么定了
So there's that.
杰西
Jesse!
Jesse.
戴上防毒面具
Respirator.
好吧
Right.
喂
Yes?
好的
Yes.
好
Okay.
我会去的
I'll be there.
什么事
What was that?
他邀请我去他家
An invitation.
你来得正是时候
Ah. Walter. You're right on time.
请进
Please, come in.
希望你喜欢海鲜汤锅[西]
I hope you like paila marina.
这是炖鱼比较好听的叫法
It's a fancy name for fish stew.
听来很老套
It sounds like a cliché,
但我母亲过去常常做这道菜
but indeed, it's just like my mother used to make it.
来吧  给我打下手
Come on. You can help me cook.
这是智利菜
This is a Chilean dish
我很喜欢
that I love,
但一直没机会做
but I never get to make it.
因为孩子们不喜欢吃
The kids won't eat it.
但是
But, uh...
你明白的
you know how that is.
当然
Sure.
来帮个忙怎样
Do you mind?
把大蒜切一下
Would you slice the garlic?
切薄一点
Very thin.
你邀我来所为何事
Why did you invite me here?
我们是生意伙伴
We're working together.
一起吃顿饭很正常吧
Why not break bread together?
切大蒜吧
Now the garlic.
人的感官与回忆之间的联系
It always amazes me the way the senses work
太神奇了
in connection to memory.
我是说  炖鱼只是一锅大杂烩
I mean, this stew is simply an amalgam of ingredients.
如果把材料分开的话
Taken separately,
不会让我回忆起任何事
these ingredients alone don't remind me of anything.
基本上不会
Not very much at all.
但一旦按这样混合起来
But, in this precise combination,
这味道就立即
the smell of this meal instantly--
让我想起了我的童年时光
it brings me back to my childhood.
真是太奇妙了
How is that possible?
大体上说  这过程发生在大脑的海马区
Basically, it all takes place in the hippocampus.
形成了神经连接
Neural connections are formed.
外界感应让神经中枢发出信号
The senses make the neurons express signals
信号传送到了大脑的之前的同一个地方
that go right back to the same part of the brain as before,
那个地方储存着人的记忆
where memory is stored.
被称为关联记忆
That's, uh, something called relational memory.
别继续问我了
don't quote me on that.
我的生物学已经忘得差不多了
I-- I'm rusty on my biology.
很有意思
That's very interesting.
沃尔特
Walter,
如果可以的话  我非常愿意帮你
I would like to help you, if I could.
怎么帮我
Help me how?
在我刚开始的时候
Well, when I first started out,
也犯了很多错误
I made a lot of mistakes.
多到我都不想承认
More than I care to admit.
真希望当时有人能提点我
I wish I'd had someone to advise me--
因为我们过的这种生活  变数太大
because this life of ours, it can overwhelm.
你现在是有钱人了
You are a wealthy man now.
你得学着怎么做有钱人
And one must learn to be rich.
穷人谁都会做
To be poor anyone can manage.
你有什么建议吗
What advice do you have for me?
同一个错别犯两次
Never make the same mistake twice.
什么事
What's up?
你是托马斯吗
You, uh, you Tomás?
我听说你就是那纯爷们
Heard you were the man.
是啊  你想要什么
Yeah? What you want?
冰毒
Crystal.
你有吗
You think you could hook me up?
300块
300.
1.75克就要300块吗
For a teenth?
靠  开玩笑呢吧
Shit, come on, yo.
300块
300.
你好
Hey, what's up?
滚吧
Bounce.